# SIVASANKARI RAJESWARAN

38 Falmouth Gardens, Redbridge, London, UK IG4 5JU | (H) 7440523130 | Shankarigg@gmail.com

# **Professional summary**

Energetic, results-driven TECHNOLOGY ANALYST, with 4+ years background in Mainframe technology and publishing domain. Core competencies include COBOL II, JCL, CICS, and IDMS as well as excellent communication and time-management skills. Proven problem solving and analytical thinking skills, fast-learning curve, and ability to update according to evolving industry trends.

## **Core Competencies**

- COBOL, JCL
- IDMS, DMLO
- SQL,DB2
- Resource Management
- Quality-control analysis

- CICS, ADSO
- SAS, REXX
- SDLC, JIRA
- Team Leadership
- Procees flow development

## Experience

### **Technology Analyst**

03/2018 to Current

Infosys limited – Bengaluru, India

- Participated in the development of product specifications and presented the best approach for the project requirement.
- Delivered the successful code for the real-time address cleansing process which in turn reduced the waiting period of the customer to get registered and resulted in capital savings of over 10%.
- Delivered superior production support for the client by assisting in the maintenance the project like fixing the abend and organized the SEV call in case of any critical discrepancies and resolved it before the customer receives the paper.
- Automated the report generation tasks and reduced the manual effort over 20%.
   Worked in AGILE methodologies.
- Engages the team with Knowledge sharing sessions results in a reduction of the single person dependency and recording of the session helps in the future reference for the newcomers.
- Constant Presentation of the road map and optimization results of every quarter resulted in the client satisfaction.

## Senior system Enginner

09/2016 to 02/2018

Infosys Limited – Bhubaneswar, India

• Involved in the feature development projects such as billing profile management of

the subscribers, and Complaint registration.

- Developed the online screens for the subscriber registration which will be used by the clients and QA team.
- Optimized the jobs that consume high CPU time, resulting in reduced congestion and increased the performance of the CPU by 10%.
- Ensure timely update of new documents to electronic versions, distribution to the
  international offices, and proactive tracking of the requirements actively worked
  upon within team to ensure the deadline is followed and have room to resolve in case
  of any discrepancies.
- Developed the USER-FRIENDLY dashboard for the subscribers/Users to acquire the basic information of the subscribers that reduced the number of tickets in the user query category by 40%.
- Handled the Finalist Software up gradation, Payment gateway up gradation, UAT testing, SOAP UI testing, and Deployment activities successfully with best outcomes.
- Completed the Intermediate level Certification on PUBLISHING DOMAIN.
- Handled the incident management tasks and familiar with JIRA, and BMC.

#### **Education**

**Bachelor Of Engineering**: Electronics and Communication Engineering **M.Kumarasamy College of Engineering** - Thalavapalayam, TN

Apr 2014

- Graduated under the stream of ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING with first-class honors
- Secured UNIVERSITY RANK HOLDER.
- Served as the Vice president of the ECE technical club during the period of 2012-2013.

GCSEs: Apr 2010

Kurinji Higher Secondary School - Namakkal, TN

- Graduated with distinction.
- Secured top rank in **MATHEMATICS**.

## Language

Fluent in Tamil, English and Hindi

#### **Awards**

Awarded as Most Valuable Player in my Unit

#### **Additional information**

- Holding TIER2 DEPENDENT UK VISA.
- Proficient in Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Excel
- LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sivasankari-rajeswaran-05241517a/